peopletopeople.com 2016-11-20

# PTPI - Privacy

**People to People International's Online Privacy Policy  
We are committed to protecting the privacy and security of the users of our sites.**

This privacy policy will advise you about how we protect your personal information, and about what choices you have concerning our use of such information. Please read this policy carefully. We may need to change this policy from time to time in order to address new issues and reflect changes on our sites. We will post those changes here so that you will always know what information we gather, how we might use that information, and whether we will disclose that information to anyone. Please refer back to this policy regularly.

**Scope of Privacy Policy**  
This policy applies to your use of our entire web site.

**Personal Identification Information**  
We may request personal identification information from you in connection with your membership in People to People International and/or your participation in one of our programs. In all of these cases, we will collect personal identification information from you only if you voluntarily submit such information to us. We will never intentionally disclose any personal identification information about you as an individual user (such as, for example, your full name, street address, telephone number, credit card number or e-mail address) to any third party without having received your permission.

If you do provide us with personal information for any of these activities, we may use it to conduct the activity. We may also use cookie technology (discussed in detail below) to improve your experience of these activities, including to remember your preferences, customize the content and advertisements that you might see or authenticate your access to your personal information. In addition, in the event your personally identifiable information is requested as part of our surveys or polls, such personally identifiable information may be added to your registration information). PTPI uses only first party non persistent cookies, which expire once the browser is closed.

We have the following exceptions to these policies: We will release specific information about you or your account to comply with any valid legal inquiry or process such as a search warrant, subpoena, statute or court order. We will also release specific information in special cases, such as if there is an attempted breach of the security of the Sites, or a physical or property threat to you or others. We may also transfer user information, including personally identifiable information, in connection with a corporate merger, consolidation, the sale of related assets or corporate division or other fundamental corporate change.

Please note that if you give out personal information online -- for example, on one of our public forums -- that information can be collected and used by third parties. Although we strive to protect our users' privacy, we cannot guarantee the security of information you post in these forums. You disclose such information at your own risk.

You are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of your information and password. You shall be responsible for all uses of your registration, whether or not authorized by you. You agree to immediately notify us of any unauthorized use of your registration or password.

**Non-Personal Identification Information**  
We may in the future collect non-personal identification information through the use of:

"Cookie" technology: A "cookie" is an element of data that a web site can send to your browser, which may then store it on your system. Most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies. You can reset your browser to refuse all cookies or indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, note that some parts of the site will not function properly or may be considerably slower if you refuse cookies.  
"IP address tracking": An IP address is a number that is assigned to your computer when you are on the Internet. When you request pages from our Sites, our servers log your IP address.

"Web beacons": A Web beacon, or "clear gif", is a small graphic image on a webpage or web-based document that a web site can use to determine information about a user.

Non-personal identification information might include the browser you use, the type of computer, technical information about your means of connection to our site-such as the operating systems and the Internet service providers utilized, and other similar information. Our systems may also automatically gather information about the areas you visit and search terms you utilize on our sites and about the links you may select from within our site to other areas of the World Wide Web or elsewhere online.

We use such information to administer the site and, in the aggregate, to understand how our users as a group use the services and resources provided on our sites. This way we know which areas of our sites are favorites of our users, which areas need improvement, and what technologies are being used so that we may continually improve our sites.

**Privacy of Children**  
WE STRONGLY RECOMMEND THAT PARENTS PARTICIPATE IN THEIR CHILDREN'S EXPLORATION OF THE INTERNET AND ANY ONLINE SERVICES AND USE THEIR BROWSER'S PARENTAL CONTROLS TO LIMIT THE AREAS OF THE INTERNET TO WHICH THEIR CHILDREN HAVE ACCESS.

We understand that young people need special safeguards and privacy protection. We realize that they may not understand all the provisions of our policy or be able to make thoughtful decisions about the choices that are made available to our adult users. We strongly urge all parents to participate in their children's exploration of the Internet and any online services, and to teach their children about protecting their personal information while online.

The Sites are not directed to children under the age of 13. We prohibit registration by children under the age of 13 for all interactive portions of the Sites including chats and message boards. We will not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under 13.

We may, at our discretion, require users under 18 to obtain the consent of a parent or legal guardian. You agree to abide by any such restrictions, and not to help anyone avoid these restrictions.

**Links To Other Sites**  
Users will find advertising or other content on our sites that link to the sites and services of our suppliers, advertisers, sponsors, licensors and other third parties. We do not control the contents or links that appear on these sites. In addition, these sites or services, including their contents and links, may be constantly changing. These sites and services may have their own privacy policies and customer service policies, or no policy (policies) at all. We encourage you to review the privacy policies of any third party sites or services before providing any of them with your personal information.

**Security Policy**  
Protecting your privacy and your information is a top priority. We have taken careful measures to secure both your information and our physical premises. We exercise great care in providing safe transmission of your information from your PC to our servers (unless sent by a means outside of our control, such as e-mail).

Once we receive your transmission, we make our best effort to ensure its security on our systems. When credit card information is transmitted, we use industry standard, SSL (secure socket layer) encryption. PTPI’s website can receive 128-bit encrypted information to ensure your personal data is protected and has a security seal from Network Solutions. We do not collect or store credit card numbers or bank account information.

Your www.ptpi.org account is password protected. We recommend that you do not divulge your password to anyone. We will never ask you for your password in an unsolicited phone call or email. Ultimately, you are responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your passwords and any account information. Remember to sign out of your account and close your browser window when you have finished your work. This is to ensure that others cannot access your personal information and correspondence if your computer is accessible to others or if you share a computer with someone else or are using a computer in a public place.  
No Liability Acts of Third Parties  
Although we will use all reasonable efforts to safeguard the confidentiality of your personal information, transmissions made by means of the Internet cannot be made absolutely secure. We will have no liability for disclosure of your personal information due to errors in transmission or unauthorized acts of third parties.

**Access To/Correction of Information**  
If you would like to review any personal information we have retained about you in our database, please send us an e-mail request for this information at membership@ptpi.org. If you are a member, this information can also be reviewed by you online in the members' only section. To help us address your request, please specify which information you wish to review. Once you have reviewed this information, at your request we will correct personal information about you that you state is erroneous. To request such a correction, please send an e-mail to membership@ptpi.org.

**Your Acceptance of These Terms**  
By using any of the Sites, you signify your acceptance of our Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to this policy, please do not use our sites. Your continued use of the Sites following the posting of changes to these terms will mean that you accept those changes.

(Last modified on October, 2009)
